<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <title>Land Use Land Cover (LULC)</title>
                <onlink>https://geodata.hawaii.gov/arcgis/rest/services/LandUseLandCover/MapServer/11</onlink>
                <onlink>https://files.hawaii.gov/dbedt/op/gis/data/lulc.pdf</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>[Metadata]  Description:  Land Use Land Cover of main Hawaiian Islands as of 1976Source:	1:100,000 1976 Digital GIRAS (Geographic Information Retrieval and Analysis) files.  Land Use and Land Cover (LULC) data consists of historical land use and land cover classification data that was based primarily on the manual interpretation of 1970's and 1980's aerial photography. Secondary sources included land use maps and surveys. There are 21 possible categories of cover type.  The spatial resolution for all LULC files will depend on the format and feature type. Files in GIRAS format will have a minimum polygon area of 10 acres (4 hectares) with a minimum width of 660 feet (200 meters) for manmade features. Non-urban or natural features have a minimum polygon area of 40 acres (16 hectares) with a minimum width of 1320 feet (400 meters). Files in CTG format will have a resolution of 30 meters. May 2024:  Hawaii Statewide GIS Program staff removed extraneous fields 
that had been added as part of the 2016 GIS database conversion and were
 no longer needed.For additional information, please refer to https://files.hawaii.gov/dbedt/op/gis/data/lulc.pdf or contact Hawaii Statewide GIS Program, Office of Planning and Sustainable Development, State of Hawaii; PO Box 2359, Honolulu, HI 96804; (808) 587-2846; email: gis@hawaii.gov; Website: https://planning.hawaii.gov/gis.</abstract>
            <purpose>Land Use Land Cover as of 1976</purpose>
        </descript>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>State of Hawaii</themekey>
                <themekey>Land Use Land Cover</themekey>
                <themekey>Niihau</themekey>
                <themekey>Kauai</themekey>
                <themekey>Oahu</themekey>
                <themekey>Molokai</themekey>
                <themekey>Lanai</themekey>
                <themekey>Maui</themekey>
                <themekey>Kahoolawe</themekey>
                <themekey>Hawaii</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>State of Hawaii Terms of Use. 



The
 contents of this web page are public domain and to the extent indicated
 otherwise in the Terms of Use, are exempt from Terms of Use policy 
restrictions.There are no expressed warranties associated with the 
release of this data or product. Specifically, no warranty is made that 
the GIS data or any subsequent updates will be error free and no 
warranty is made regarding the positional or thematic accuracy of the 
GIS data. The GIS data and any features depicted do not represent or 
confer any legal rights, privileges, benefits, boundaries or claims of 
any kind. The Office of Planning and Sustainable Development encourages users to report any 
discrepancies or errors found. 
 Contact: Hawaii Statewide GIS Program, Office of Planning and 
Sustainable Development, State of Hawaii; PO Box 2359, Honolulu, Hi. 
96804; (808) 587-2846; email: gis@hawaii.gov. Website: https://planning.hawaii.gov/gis.</useconst>
        <datacred>Hawaii Statewide GIS Program</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20201101</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
